<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Morten Jensen</title>
    <link>https://jensenmo.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Morten Jensen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jensenmo.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Use the Raspberry Pi 4 for AWS development - Part 1, Installation</title>
      <link>https://jensenmo.github.io/posts/use-raspberry-pi-for-aws-development-part-1-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensenmo.github.io/posts/use-raspberry-pi-for-aws-development-part-1-install/</guid>
      <description>Background With the advent of the Raspberry Pi 4, Pi&amp;rsquo;s have sufficiently powerful in terms of both CPU and memory for AWS development. Furthermore, AWS has recently made significant headway in the ARM space with the release of Graviton-based EC2 and support for ARM 64-bit (aarch64) with the following services:
 AWS CodeBuild Amazon EKS worker nodes (beta preview) AWS ECS (for EC2) ARM AMIs  Currently, there&amp;rsquo;s no known way to run Amazon Linux 2 on a Raspberry Pi (but AMI&amp;rsquo;s will run on Graviton-based EC2 instances in AWS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get started with Ubuntu 20.04 on Raspberry Pi 4</title>
      <link>https://jensenmo.github.io/posts/get-started-with-ubuntu-on-raspberry-pi-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensenmo.github.io/posts/get-started-with-ubuntu-on-raspberry-pi-4/</guid>
      <description>Background With the advent of the Raspberry Pi 4, Pi&amp;rsquo;s have become quite powerful both in CPU and memory terms and are now good candidates for software development on ARM architecture. The Pi 4 boasts quad-core ARM v8 1.5Ghz CPU with 64-bit support and the option of 2, 4 or 8GB of DDR4 memory. It also has excellent connectivity through dual HDMI support (including 4k), Gigabit Ethernet and USB 3.0 (and 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install &amp; run AWS Glue 1.0 and PySpark on Ubuntu 20.04</title>
      <link>https://jensenmo.github.io/posts/install-glue-on-ubuntu-20.04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensenmo.github.io/posts/install-glue-on-ubuntu-20.04/</guid>
      <description>Background It&amp;rsquo;s much faster to be able to develop and debug AWS Glue / PySpark scripts locally.
The Developing and Testing ETL Scripts Locally Using the AWS Glue ETL Library instructions describe installation but are not complete. There are certain dependencies to consider to make this work.
Also note that the version of PySpark used (2.4.3) for Glue 1.0 does not support:
 Python 3.8, which Ubuntu 20.04 comes with. Therefore some of the PySpark code needs to be hacked a bit as per Stackoverflow and Gist.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
